Control Input Variations
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
Recall that we've been through the specific steps.
Having just looked at improve action settings.
Now, one of the key elements that must occur is to control input variation.
Relative to those settings.
See now, those settings in turn, determine what the force will be
for each opportunity condition.
Which in turn makes change. Which leads to satisfying needs.
So, let's look at that now, as we reduce variation
around an action setting, a better action setting, a superior action setting.
The force improves for the condition
associated with the opportunity for change.
That in turn, if we can make that change, satisfies the needs.
That's really what we're looking at here. So now, let’s look on to controlling input variations.
Recall that we had talked about the example of a newspaper, getting a job.
And that to get an opportunity means we gotta be able to get the newspaper.
But we said, what if there's a dog out there that chews it up
because the newspaper comes at 8 o’clock in the morning. Well, change the time.
So, what we did is we improved that action setting.
We moved it from 8 o'clock in the morning to 6 o'clock in the morning.
Now, what I'm going to do is to put a little bit more understanding around that.
I’m going to come over here and I'm gonna put this scale out, called 8 o'clock a.m.
And remember, we want to change here now to 6 o'clock a.m.
We want to move the time the newspaper is delivered
from eight to six. And recall, that's a gap.
We gotta close that gap.
And Y is a function of X. And remember, this is a gap on the X side. I’m just refreshing us.
Now, around that 6 o'clock, there’s variation.
In other words, some mornings, the paper may come at this time.
Other mornings, it may come at this time. So there's a window of variation.
There’s variation around that time.
So, the more that we move in this direction, the greater the probability is
the next door neighbor’s dog is going to chew it up. And that could very well be. Murphy's Law.
The day the newspaper ad comes out for the job we needed.
See. So we gotta remove that variation.
We don't want variation around these action settings.
Recall, that's an action setting.
That's an action setting. We changed the action setting.
And this is the new one. This is the improved action setting.
And we don't want variation around it. So, what do we do?
Well, let’s think about that a second. Those three words. Those key three words.
Improve. Action.
Settings.
And I add to that, for each critical condition. Whoops, remember that?
In Six Sigma work, we had critical to value, critical to quality.
Now, we have a critical condition.
For which there is an optimal setting for that critical condition.
That setting is an action setting, and we have to improve it.
We’ve gotta take it from where it was, to where we need it to be.
And then minimize the variation around it.
That's absolutely essential. That's what we mean by improve action settings.
Now remember, if we do that,
and control input variations. Control our input variations.
Now remember, if we do that. If we reduce input variations,
then we more assuredly keep the optimal settings.
Associated with each of the forces.
That constitutes the conditions
or opportunities as we call them.
To satisfy our needs.
See that's so simple the way it works.
As a matter of fact, it's so simple it's almost embarrassingly simple.
But you know something? Some of the greatest things are
when the not so obvious becomes obvious.
I love it when people used to tell me about the old breakthrough strategy I invented.
Define, measure, analyze, improve, control. They said, well, we understand that.
My question was, well then, why haven't you been doing for the last 30 years?
Well, that's a part of when something is really good.
When you're able to find simple things and make them obvious.
Bring them from the subconscious to the conscious level.
See, that's all this strategy is really doing.
Many of us already do this in a subconscious way,
but to make it teachable and understandable, to make it habit.
Listen to that. To make it habit, we gotta consciously do it time and time again.
We gotta remove variations around the optimal settings,
for those forces that constitutes the vital few conditions,
of the key opportunities, associated with the value needs that we have in our life.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.